N.CHOLA RAJU

web developer

14-1 veldurthi kurnool district Andhra pradesh 518216

Email: rajuneluri@gmail.com

phone:7981097400

web:https://hashnode.com/@chola

profile

Senior Software Developer with 3+ years of experience in Web Development. Skilled with JavaScript, TypeScript, React.js, Redux, React Context and Hooks. Rest APIs, SQL Server. Enthusiast in NodeJS and Micro-Services Architecture. Able to stretch the boundaries of web development and best coding practices to maintain the clean code to stand out and grow. currently seeking a platform to boost my career in Full stack development.

skills

- html
- CSS
- javascript
- reactjs
- nodejs
- expressjs
- sql & no sql
- mongodb

Work Experience

2021-present aspire systems

sr web devloper roles &responsibilites

- Worked on developing the React.js components for the payment screens and redirecting flows in the application.
- Part of a team, where we focus to build re-usable web components in React.js
- Experienced in understanding the Business Logic and translating to technical approaches, outlining the flow to Implement the features in Application. Experienced in MERN stack tasks in developing the modules of Application
- . Worked on configuring the APIs in the node.js to interact with Redis using hapi.js framework.
- Collaborates with QA team to resolve bugs identified, followed by UAT

jr web devloper roles & responsibilites

2019 - 2021 redim-information technologies chennai

- Built dashboards for monitoring the application and dashboard actions to control the traffic flow to the application.
- Experienced in developing web pages using HTML5, CSS3, SCSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize CSS.
- Experienced in all phase of SDLC including Requirement Analysis and tasks refinement sessions.
- Implemented re-usable Materialize plugins for static sites.
- · Performed the Unit Testing, functional testing using jest.
- Involved direct interactions with various clients to integrate the APIs and releasing the production builds.
- · Worked in the production Maintenance and Deployments.
- Sprint Planning, reviews, assignments and prioritization of tasks and audits are managed in jira

projects

ReDIM Information Systems, Chennai Clients: Asiabet, Bet365, Dafabet, PrimeExchange, Jack-Henry and Co.

Project name: Ho-Gaming

Project Description: HO-Gaming is an online casino Gaming platform where users can place bets with real currency and play RNG game

Project Name: Super Spade Games
Project Description: Super Spade Games is an online casino Gaming
platform where users can place bets with real currency and play

the games like Andar- Bahar, Dragon tiger and Roulette

DEVELOPER May 2021 - Present
project name :ZELLEPAY -TOOLKIT

project name :ZELLEPAY -TOOLKIT
Project Description: Zellepay is a payments app where users can
integrate with different bank accounts, send and receive money
from the people across the globe.

EDUCATION: 2014-2018